<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Physics on home</title>
    <link>https://maxawake.github.io/tags/physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Physics on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maxawake.github.io/tags/physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vlasov-Poisson Simulation with Python</title>
      <link>https://maxawake.github.io/post/2024/10/12/simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxawake.github.io/post/2024/10/12/simulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;solving-the-vlasov-poisson-equation-using-python&#34;&gt;Solving the Vlasov-Poisson equation using Python&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A plasma is a quasi-neutral gas of charged and neutral particles showing non-trivial collective behavior, distinct from other states of matter. The dynamics of plasma can be derived from the Boltzmann equation, where we can usually assume that we have a negligible amount of collisions. This leads us to the collisionless Boltzmann or &lt;strong&gt;Vlasov equation&lt;/strong&gt;. In this tutorial, we want to simulate a simple one-dimensional plasma using the Vlasov equation and look at Landau damping and two kinetic instabilities. Since in one dimension we can&amp;rsquo;t have any magnetic fields, we actually solve the electrostatic Vlasov-Poisson equation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dark Energy Potentials via Symbolic Regression and Bayesian Inference</title>
      <link>https://maxawake.github.io/post/2023/08/30/dark-energy-potentials-via-symbolic-regression-and-bayesian-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 11:33:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxawake.github.io/post/2023/08/30/dark-energy-potentials-via-symbolic-regression-and-bayesian-inference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;machine-learning-quintessence-dark-energy-potentials-via-symbolic-regression-and-bayesian-inference&#34;&gt;Machine Learning Quintessence Dark Energy Potentials via Symbolic Regression and Bayesian Inference&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quintessence is a hypothesized scalar field forming a popular model for dark energy, the nonluminous energy density in the Universe responsible for the accelerated expansion of space.&#xA;This field can change in time and henceforth solve difficulties arising in the ΛCDM standard&#xA;model. The dynamics of the field are governed by its self-interaction potential. To infer the&#xA;form of this potential by observational data, we construct a suitable potential using machine&#xA;learning and derive the observable quantities then numerically. Symbolic regression is a form&#xA;of supervised learning, with the aim of finding the most likely symbolic representations of&#xA;mathematical models for a given data set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
